BU Records: Baylor Orators Toastmasters Club, Inclusive: 2003-2013
Baylor University, The Texas Collection
BU Records: Baylor Orators Toastmasters Club
Inclusive: 2003-2013
Baylor University, The Texas Collection http://www.baylor.edu/lib/texas/
BU/387
Baylor University
4 document boxes
BU Records: Baylor Orators Toastmasters Club covers the founding of the professional development society through its chartering as an official club and its first decade of existence
Administrative Information
Physical Description
General condition: Excellent.
Biography/Profile
The Toastmasters Club was founded by Dr. Ralph C. Smedley on 1924 October 22 in Santa Anna, California. The group was founded in order to teach young people skills in public speaking, leadership, and collaboration. By 1930, the organization had expanded to have around 30 affiliated clubs in the USA and Canada and in 1932, it was incorporated as a non-profit under the name of Toastmasters International. Today, there are over 358,000 members in 16,800 clubs based in 70 different countries.
The Baylor chapter of the Toastmasters was charted on 2003 March 27 with 22 members. It continues to meet on the campus of Baylor University.
Scope and Content
BU Records: Baylor Orators Toastmasters Club begins in 2003 and ends in 2013. The materials detail the day-to-day running of the organization from its chartering through the first decade of its existence. There is one series in this collection entitled "Administrative Files". This series contains the minutes from both the weekly and officer meetings as well as the treasurer reports.
Access Restrictions
All requests for copying of materials must be submitted to The Texas Collection in writing. Please use the Request Form for Copying Materials sheet. Unpublished materials authored or otherwise produced by the creator (s) of this collection are in the public domain. There are no restrictions on use. Copyright status for other collection materials is unknown. Transmission or reproduction of materials protected by U.S. Copyright Law (Title 17, U.S.C.) beyond that allowed by fair use requires the written permission of the copyright owners. Works not in the public domain cannot be commercially exploited without permission of the copyright owners. Responsibility for any use rests exclusively with the user.
Acquisition Information
Accession No. BU/387. Acquired 2016-03-04
Related Resources
Related references
"A Brief History of the Toastmasters Program" Baylor University. Accessed 2019 August 28.
BU Records: Baylor Orators Toastmasters Club, Accession #BU/387, Box 1, Folder 1, The Texas Collection, Baylor University.
"The Toastmasters Journey" Toastmasters International. Accessed 2019 August 28.
Index Terms
Subjects (Organizations)
Toastmasters International.
Subjects
Public speaking -- Societies and clubs.; Public speaking.
Genres
Minutes (Records)
- Administrative Files, 2003-2013; 1
  Administrative Information
  Physical Description
  General condition: Excellent.
  Biography/Profile
  This series contains the minutes of club meetings, correspondence, and financial records such as receipts, bank statements, and members' dues records. The series is in excellent condition.
  - Minutes (1 of 2), 2003 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Minutes (2 of 2), 2003 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Minutes (1 of 4), 2003 July-2004 June (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Minutes (2 of 4), 2003 July-2004 June (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - Minutes (3 of 4), 2003 July-2004 June (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - Minutes (4 of 4), 2003 July-2004 June (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - Minutes (1 of 4), 2004 July-2005 June (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - Minutes (2 of 4), 2004 July-2005 June (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - Minutes (3 of 4), 2004 July-2005 June (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - Minutes (4 of 4), 2004 July-2005 June (Box 2, Folder 1)
  - Minutes (1 of 4), 2005-July-2006 June (Box 2, Folder 2)
  - Minutes (2 of 4), 2005-July-2006 June (Box 2, Folder 3)
  - Minutes (3 of 4), 2005-July-2006 June (Box 2, Folder 4)
  - Minutes (4 of 4), 2005-July-2006 June (Box 2, Folder 5)
  - Minutes (1 of 4), 2006 July-2007 June (Box 2, Folder 6)
  - Minutes (2 of 4), 2006 July-2007 June (Box 2, Folder 7)
  - Minutes (3 of 4), 2006 July-2007 June (Box 2, Folder 8)
  - Minutes (4 of 4), 2006 July-2007 June (Box 2, Folder 9)
  - Minutes (1 of 2), 2008 July-2009 June (Box 3, Folder 1)
  - Minutes (2 of 2), 2008 July-2009 June (Box 3, Folder 2)
  - Minutes (1 of 3), 2009 July-2010 June (Box 3, Folder 3)
  - Minutes (2 of 3), 2009 July-2010 June (Box 3, Folder 4)
  - Minutes (3 of 3), 2009 July-2010 June (Box 3, Folder 5)
  - Minutes (1 of 3), 2010 July-2011 June (Box 3, Folder 6)
  - Minutes (2 of 3) (Box 3, Folder 7)
  - Minutes (3 of 3) (Box 3, Folder 8)
  - Minutes (1 of 5), 2011-2013 (Box 4, Folder 1)
  - Minutes (2 of 5), 2011-2013 (Box 4, Folder 2)
  - Minutes (3 of 5), 2011-2013 (Box 4, Folder 3)
  - Minutes (4 of 5), 2011-2013 (Box 4, Folder 4)
  - Minutes (5 of 5), 2011-2013 (Box 4, Folder 5)
  - Treasurer Reports (1 of 2), 2003 July-2004 June (Box 4, Folder 6)
  - Treasurer Reports (2 of 2), 2003 July-2004 June (Box 4, Folder 7)